<metadata xml:lang="en">
  <Esri>
    <CreaDate>20081006</CreaDate>
    <CreaTime>11514500</CreaTime>
    <SyncDate>20020214</SyncDate>
    <SyncTime>18442600</SyncTime>
    <ModDate>20080930</ModDate>
    <ModTime>14493400</ModTime>
    <Sync>FALSE</Sync>
    <MetaID>{E3BA73F1-4798-4FA8-81D4-0B41D2F01038}</MetaID>
    <SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce>
    <PublishedDocID>{0ACAE407-9042-4A52-8378-95837A7EB6ED}</PublishedDocID>
    <PublishStatus>Published</PublishStatus>
  </Esri>
  <idinfo>
    <native Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.1.3.679</native>
    <descript>
      <langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata>
      <abstract>U.S. Telephone Area Code Boundaries represents the telephone area codes for United States. They are also known as Numbering Plan Areas (NPA).</abstract>
      <purpose>U.S. Telephone Area Code Boundaries provides the telephone area codes of United States for use in telecommunications analysis.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:250,000.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Geographic Data Technology, Inc. (GDT)</origin>
        <pubdate>20020401</pubdate>
        <title>U.S. Telephone Area Code Boundaries 2002</title>
        <ftname Sync="TRUE">areacode</ftname>
        <geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform>
        <edition>2002</edition>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>
          <issue>2002</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</origin>
        <onlink>http://map.princeton.edu/data/4f/16/c4/23/m/content/restricted/data.zip</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <timeperd>
      <current>publication date</current>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>200201</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Matches software update releases</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc Sync="TRUE">-178.229649</westbc>
        <eastbc Sync="TRUE">-66.949895</eastbc>
        <northbc Sync="TRUE">71.381773</northbc>
        <southbc Sync="TRUE">18.910842</southbc>
      </bounding>
      <lboundng>
        <leftbc Sync="TRUE">-178.229649</leftbc>
        <rightbc Sync="TRUE">-66.949895</rightbc>
        <bottombc Sync="TRUE">18.910842</bottombc>
        <topbc Sync="TRUE">71.381773</topbc>
      </lboundng>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>polygon</themekey>
        <themekey>area codes</themekey>
        <themekey>telephones</themekey>
        <themekey>numbering plan areas</themekey>
        <themekey>utilitiesCommunication</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkey>2002</tempkey>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
    <useconst>The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps CD&#8211;ROMs for use with ESRI&#174; software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps CD&#8211;ROMs. As used herein, &#8220;Geodata&#8221; shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this data set: Redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor for hard-copy renditions or static, electronic map images (e.g. .gif, .jpeg, etc.) that are plotted, printed, or publicly displayed with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).  Geodata is redistributable with a Value-Added Software Application developed by ESRI Business Partners on a royalty-free basis with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).

Special notice from Geographic Data Technology, Inc. for this data set:
This product contains information and/or data of Telcordia Technologies, Inc. (&#8220;Telcordia&#8221;) licensed to be included herein. Recipient acknowledges and agrees that (1) TELCORDIA AND ITS AFFILIATES MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS, EXTEND NO WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, AND ASSUME NO RESPONSIBILITY OR LIABILITY WHATSOEVER WITH RESPECT TO THE USE, SUFFICIENCY OR ACCURACY OF THE PRODUCT, (2) RECIPIENT SHALL MAKE NO CLAIM AGAINST TELCORDIA OR ANY OF ITS AFFILIATES WITH RESPECT TO THE PRODUCT, AND WAIVES ALL CLAIMS AGAINST TELCORDIA OR ANY OF ITS AFFILIATES WITH RESPECT TO THE PRODUCT, (3) IN NO EVENT SHALL TELCORDIA OR ANY OF ITS AFFILIATES BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES, INCLUDING ANY LOST PROFITS OR OTHER INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES RELATING TO THE PRODUCT, AND, (4) THIS AGREEMENT SHALL BE ENFORCEABLE BY TELCORDIA.

The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on the ESRI Data &amp; Maps CD&#8211;ROMs.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>
    <natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform>
    <datacred>Telcordia Technologies, Inc.; North American Numbering Plan (Association); Local Exchange Routing Guide</datacred>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Princeton University Library</cntorg>
          <cntper>Tsering Wangyal Shawa</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntvoice>609-258-6804</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>shawatw@oprinceton.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>8:45 a.m.&#8211;5:00 p.m. EST, Monday&#8211;Friday</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
  </idinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta>
    <metstdn Sync="TRUE">FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv Sync="TRUE">FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Digital Map and Geospatial Information Center, The Lewis Library, Room 228, Princeton University</address>
          <city>Princeton</city>
          <state>NJ</state>
          <postal>08544</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntper>Tsering Wangyal Shawa</cntper>
          <cntorg>Princeton University Library</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntvoice>609-258-6804</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>shawatw@princeton,.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>8:45 a.m.&#8211;5:00 p.m. EST, Monday&#8211;Friday</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metd Sync="TRUE">20080930</metd>
    <metextns>
      <onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct Sync="TRUE">Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <esriterm Name="areacode">
        <efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp>
        <efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polygon</efeageom>
        <esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo>
        <efeacnt Sync="TRUE">269</efeacnt>
        <spindex Sync="TRUE">TRUE</spindex>
        <linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer>
        <featdesc>U.S. Telephone Area Code Boundary</featdesc>
      </esriterm>
      <sdtsterm Name="areacode">
        <sdtstype Sync="TRUE">G-polygon</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">269</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <cordsysn>
        <geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn>
      </cordsysn>
      <geograph>
        <geogunit Sync="TRUE">Decimal degrees</geogunit>
        <latres Sync="TRUE">0.000001</latres>
        <longres Sync="TRUE">0.000001</longres>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn Sync="TRUE">North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips Sync="TRUE">Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis Sync="TRUE">6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat Sync="TRUE">298.257222</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed Name="areacode">
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl Sync="TRUE">areacode</enttypl>
        <enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt>
        <enttypc Sync="TRUE">269</enttypc>
        <enttypd>The polygons represent the telephone area codes within United States.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth>
        <atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis>
        <attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale>
        <attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth>
        <atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis>
        <attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale>
        <attrdef Sync="TRUE">Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom Sync="TRUE">Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">NPA</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">NPA</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">3</attwidth>
        <attrdef>The telephone area code (Numbering Plan Area (NPA) code).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">STATE</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">STATE</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">2</attwidth>
        <attrdef>The FIPS code (two-digit number) for the state in which the telephone area code is located.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">TYPE</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">TYPE</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">1</attwidth>
        <attrdef>The way a new telephone area code is created.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>O</edomv>
            <edomvd>The new telephone area code is overlaid on the existing telephone area code.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>S</edomv>
            <edomvds>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</edomvds>
            <edomvd>The new telephone area code is split from the existing telephone area code.</edomvd>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">BEGINDIAL</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">BEGINDIAL</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth>
        <attrdef>The date the telephone area code becomes effective.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Dates for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">PREVNPA</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">PREVNPA</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">3</attwidth>
        <attrdef>The telephone area code (Numbering Plan Area (NPA) code) that was used previously for this area.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">ENDDIAL</attrlabl>
        <attalias Sync="TRUE">ENDDIAL</attalias>
        <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
        <attwidth Sync="TRUE">20</attwidth>
        <attrdefs>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</attrdefs>
        <attrdef>The date the previous telephone area code expires.</attrdef>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Dates for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <dataqual>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <title>GDT Dynamap/Telecommunication Products v6.0</title>
            <origin>Geographic Data Technology, Inc.</origin>
            <pubdate>200201</pubdate>
            <edition>Version 6.0</edition>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>Dynamap&#174;/Telecommunication Products</sername>
              <issue>v6.0</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <publish>Geographic Data Technology, Inc</publish>
              <pubplace>Lebanon, New Hampshire, USA</pubplace>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>CD&#8211;ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>200201</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>GDT Dynamap/Telecommunication Products v6.0</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The source of the Numbering Plan Areas (NPA) data is both North American Numbering Plan Association (NANPA) and the Local Exchange Routing Guide. We work closely with NANPA to keep these boundaries as accurate as possible.

There is really no source scale since the data is related to us as "a certain Rate Center is within a certain NPA area". The accuracy of the Rate Center and therefore the NPA boundaries is better defined by their position relative to other features. In other words, whether or not the boundary follows a street or a county boundary is the important factor.</procdesc>
        <procsv>ArcView GIS 3.x</procsv>
        <srcprod>GDT Dynamap/Telecommunication Products v6.0</srcprod>
        <procdate>2001</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The horizontal positional accuracy is difficult to determine since the boundaries may follow state, county, city, or other political boundaries. Still other times they may follow streets or other linear features in the database. Since these features are derived from different sources, it is not possible to give a single overall figure for horizontal accuracy.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <logic>No duplicate features are present.</logic>
    <complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
  </dataqual>
  <mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20080930</mdDateSt>
  <Binary>
    <Thumbnail />
  </Binary>
  <dataIdInfo>
    <envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 2; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.1.3.679</envirDesc>
    <dataLang>
      <languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en" />
    </dataLang>
    <idCitation>
      <resTitle Sync="TRUE">areacode</resTitle>
      <presForm>
        <PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005" />
      </presForm>
    </idCitation>
    <spatRpType>
      <SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" />
    </spatRpType>
    <geoBox esriExtentType="native">
      <westBL Sync="TRUE">-178.2296</westBL>
      <eastBL Sync="TRUE">-66.9499</eastBL>
      <northBL Sync="TRUE">18.91084</northBL>
      <southBL Sync="TRUE">71.38177</southBL>
      <exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode>
    </geoBox>
    <geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees">
      <westBL Sync="TRUE">-178.2296</westBL>
      <eastBL Sync="TRUE">-66.9499</eastBL>
      <northBL Sync="TRUE">18.91084</northBL>
      <southBL Sync="TRUE">71.38177</southBL>
      <exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode>
    </geoBox>
  </dataIdInfo>
  <mdLang>
    <languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en" />
  </mdLang>
  <mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName>
  <mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer>
  <mdFileID Sync="TRUE">{1F7DDF21-BC01-4C20-8AA5-243B33ED0B1E}</mdFileID>
  <mdChar>
    <CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" />
  </mdChar>
  <mdHrLv>
    <ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005" />
  </mdHrLv>
  <mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName>
  <distInfo>
    <distributor>
      <distorTran>
        <onLineSrc>
          <orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc>
          <protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol>
          <linkage Sync="TRUE">file://</linkage>
        </onLineSrc>
        <tranSize Sync="TRUE">31.064</tranSize>
      </distorTran>
      <distorFormat>
        <formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName>
      </distorFormat>
    </distributor>
  </distInfo>
  <refSysInfo>
    <RefSystem>
      <refSysID>
        <identCode Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</identCode>
      </refSysID>
    </RefSystem>
  </refSysInfo>
  <spatRepInfo>
    <VectSpatRep>
      <topLvl>
        <TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" />
      </topLvl>
      <geometObjs Name="areacode">
        <geoObjTyp>
          <GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" />
        </geoObjTyp>
        <geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">269</geoObjCnt>
      </geometObjs>
    </VectSpatRep>
  </spatRepInfo>
  <distinfo>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
  </distinfo>
</metadata>