<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
				<pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
				<title>New Jersey Digital Orthophotoquad, 1995-97</title>
				<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
					<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<onlink>https://njgin.state.nj.us/NJ_NJGINExplorer/index.jsp</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>Orthophotos combine the image characteristics of a
photograph with the geometric qualities of a map. The
primary digital orthophotoquad (DOQ) is a 1-meter ground
resolution, quarter-quadrangle (3.75-minutes of latitude
by 3.75-minutes of longitude) image cast on the Universal
Transverse Mercator Projection (UTM) on the North
American Datum of 1983 (NAD83).The geographic extent of
the DOQ is equivalent to a quarter-quad plus The overedge
ranges a minimum of 50 meters to a maximum of 300 meters
beyond the extremes of the primary and secondary corner
points. The overedge is included to facilitate tonal
matching for mosaicking and for the placement of the NAD83
and secondary datum corner ticks. The normal orientation
of data is by lines (rows) and samples (columns). Each
line contains a series of pixels ordered from west to
east with the order of the lines from north to south.
The standard, archived digital orthophoto is formatted as
four ASCII header records, followed by a series of 8-bit
binary image data records. The radiometric image
brightness values are stored as 256 gray levels ranging
from 0 to 255. The metadata provided in the digital
orthophoto contain a wide range of descriptive
information including format source information,
production instrumentation and dates, and data to assist
with displaying and georeferencing the image. The
standard distribution format of DOQs will be JPEG
compressed images on CD-ROM by counties or special
regions. The reconstituted image from the CD-ROM will
exhibit some radiometric differences when compared to its
uncompressed original but will retain the geometry of the
uncompressed DOQ. Uncompressed DOQs are distributed on
tape.</abstract>
			<purpose>DOQ's serve a variety of purposes, from interim maps to
field references for earth science investigations and
analysis. The DOQ is useful as a layer of a geographic
information system and as a tool for revision of digital
line graphs and topographic maps.</purpose>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<rngdates>
					<begdate>19940222</begdate>
				</rngdates>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>ground condition</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>In work</progress>
			<update>Irregular</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>-75.5794</westbc>
				<eastbc>-73.8908</eastbc>
				<northbc>41.4212</northbc>
				<southbc>38.9176</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>None</themekt>
				<themekey>DOQ</themekey>
				<themekey>DOQQ</themekey>
				<themekey>digital orthophoto</themekey>
				<themekey>digital orthophotoquad</themekey>
				<themekey>digital image map</themekey>
				<themekey>aerial photograph</themekey>
				<themekey>rectified photograph</themekey>
				<themekey>rectified image</themekey>
				<themekey>orthophoto</themekey>
				<themekey>quarter-quadrangle orthophoto</themekey>
				<themekey>1-meter orthophoto</themekey>
				<themekey>2-meter orhtophoto</themekey>
				<themekey>3.75- x 3.75-minute orthophoto</themekey>
				<themekey>7.5- x 7.5-minute orthophoto</themekey>
				<themekey>imageryBaseMapsEarthCover</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekey>New Jersey</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce, 1987, Codes for the identificationof the States, the District of Columbia  and the outlying areas ofThe United States, and associated areas(Federal Information Processing Standard 5-2):  Washington, D. C.,National Institute of Standards and Technology.</placekt>
				<placekey>FIPS code of State or Province</placekey>
			</place>
			<place>
				<placekt>U.S. Department of Commerce,1990, Counties and equivalententities of The United States, its possessions, and associated areas(Federal    Information Processing Standard 6-4):  Washington, D.C.National Institute of Standards and Technology.</placekt>
				<placekey>FIPS code for county or counties.</placekey>
			</place>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>None</accconst>
		<useconst>None. Acknowledgement of the U.S. Geological Survey would beappreciated in products derived from these data.</useconst>
		<native>Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 4; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.0.0.535</native>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<attracc>
			<attraccr>During photographic reproduction of the source photography,
limited analog dodging is performed to improve image quality.
Analog dodging consists of holding back light from certain
areas of the sensitized photographic material to avoid
overexposure. The diapositive is inspected to insure clarity
and radiometric uniformity. Diapositive image brightness
values are collected with a minimum of image quality manipulation.
Image brightness values may deviate from brightness values of
the original imagery due to image value interpolation during
the scanning and rectification processes.
Radiometry is verified by visual inspection of the digital
orthophoto quadrangle with the original unrectified image to
determine if the digital orthophoto has the same or better
image quality as the original unrectified input image.
Slight systematic radiometric differences can be detected
between adjacent DOQ files due primarily to differences in
source photography capture dates and sun angles of aerial
photography along flight lines. These differences can be
observed in an image's general lightness or darkness when
compared to adjacent DOQ file coverages.</attraccr>
		</attracc>
		<logic>All DOQ header data and image file sizes are validated by the Tape
Validation System (TVS) software prior to archiving in the National
Digital Cartographic Data Base (NDCDB). This validation procedure assures
correct physical format and field values for header record elements.
Logical relationships between header record elements are tested.</logic>
		<complete>All DOQ imagery is visually inspected for completeness to ensure that no
gaps, or image misplacement exist in the 3.75' image area or in overedge
coverage. DOQ images may be derived by mosaicking multiple images, in
order to insure complete coverage. All DOQ's are cloud free within the
3.75' image area. Some clouds may, very infrequently, be encountered only
in the overedge coverage. Source photography is leaf-off in deciduous
vegetation regions.  Void areas having a radiometric value of zero and
appearing black may exist.  These are areas for which no photographic
source is available or result from image transformation from other
planimetric systems to the Universal Transverse Mercator (UTM). In the
latter case, the void sliver areas are on the outside edges of the
overedge area.  The data set field content of each DOQ header record
element is validated to assure completeness prior to archiving in the
NDCDB.</complete>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>The DOQ horizontal positional accuracy and the assurance of that
accuracy depend, in part, on the accuracy of the data inputs to the
rectification process. These inputs consist of the digital elevation
model (DEM),aerotriangulation control and methods, the photo source
camera calibration, scanner calibration, and aerial photographs that
meet National Aerial Photography Program (NAPP) standards. The
vertical accuracy of the verified USGS format DEM is equivalent to or
better than a USGS level 1 or 2 DEM, with a root mean square error
(RMSE) of no greater than 7.0 meters. Field control is acquired by
third order class 1 or better survey methods sufficiently spaced to
meet National Map Accuracy Staandards (NMAS) for 1:12,000-scale
products.  Aerial cameras have current certification from the USGS,
National Mapping Division, Optical Science Laboratory. Test
calibration scans are performed on all source photography scanners.</horizpar>
			</horizpa>
		</posacc>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
						<pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
						<title>digital elevation model</title>
						<geoform>map</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
						</pubinfo>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>cartridge tape</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>19880805</begdate>
							<enddate>Present</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>DEM1</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Elevation data in the form of an ortho-DEM regridded
to user-specified intervals and bounds.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
						<pubdate>Unknown</pubdate>
						<title>photo ID number</title>
						<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
						</pubinfo>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>40000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>cartridge tape</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>Unknown</begdate>
							<enddate>Present</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>PHOTO1</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Panchromatic black and white (or color infra-red)
NAPP or NAPP-like photograph. NAPP photographs are
centered on the DOQ coverage area.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
						<pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate>
						<title>project ground and photo control</title>
						<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
						</pubinfo>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>various media</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>Unknown</begdate>
							<enddate>Present</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>CONTROL_INPUT</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Horizontal and vertical control used
to establish positions and elevations for reference and
correlation purposes.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>U.S. Geological Survey</origin>
						<pubdate>Unpublished material</pubdate>
						<title>report of calibration</title>
						<geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Reston, VA</pubplace>
							<publish>U.S. Geological Survey</publish>
						</pubinfo>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>disc, paper</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>Unknown</begdate>
							<enddate>Present</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>Date of the camera calibration associated with the source</srccurr>
				</srctime>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Metadata imported.</procdesc>
				<srcused>C:\DOCUME~1\GISSTU~1\LOCALS~1\Temp\xml36.tmp</srcused>
			</procstep>
		</lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<geograph>
				<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
			</geograph>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>North American Datum 1983</horizdn>
				<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298.257</denflat>
			</geodetic>
		</horizsys>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<overview>
			<eaover>For DOQ's from panchromatic source each pixel contains an
8-bit gray-scale value between 0-255. A value of 0 represents
the color black while a value of 255 represents the color white.
All values between 0 and 255 are repesented as a shade of gray
varying from black to white. For color-infrared and natural color
DOQs' a digital number from 0 to 255 will also be
asssigned to each pixel but that number will refer to a color
look-up table which will contain the RGB red, blue and green
(RGB) values, each from 0 to 255, for that digital number. Areas
where the rectification process is incomplete due to incomplete data
(i.e., lack of elevation data, gaps), are represented with the numeric
value of 0.</eaover>
			<eadetcit>U.S. Department of the Interior,  U.S. Geological Survey,
guide for digital orthophotos: Reston, VA.

A hypertext version is available at:
URL: http://edcwww.cr.usgs.gov/glis/hyper/guide/usgs_doq

U.S. Department of the Interior,  U.S. Geological Survey, 1992,
Standards for digital orthophotos: Reston, VA.

Softcopies in ASCII, WordPerfect, and PostScript format are available at:
URL: ftp://mapping.usgs.gov/pub/ti/DOQ/</eadetcit>
		</overview>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Earth Science Information Center, U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>Complete list of Earth Science Information Centers at:URL: http://mapping.usgs.gov/esic/esic_index.html</address>
					<address>507 National Center</address>
					<city>Reston</city>
					<state>VA</state>
					<postal>20192</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>1 800 USA MAPS</cntvoice>
				<hours>0800-1600</hours>
				<cntinst>In addition to the address above there are other ESIC offices
throughout the country.  A full list of these offices is at:

URL: http://mapping.usgs.gov/esic/esic_index.html</cntinst>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<resdesc>Geographic Services</resdesc>
		<distliab>Although these data have been processed successfully on a computer
system at the U.S. Geological Survey no warranty expressed or
implied is made by the USGS regarding the utility of the data on any
other system, nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such
warranty. The USGS will warrant the delivery of this product in
computer-readable format and will offer appropriate adjustment
of credit when the product is determined unreadable by correctly
adjusted computer input peripherals, or when the physical medium
is delivered in damaged condition. Requests for adjustments of
credit must be made within 90 days from the date of this shipment
from the ordering site.</distliab>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20041112</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>U.S. Geological Survey</cntorg>
					<cntper>REQUIRED: The person responsible for the metadata information.</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing address</addrtype>
					<address>508 National Center</address>
					<city>Reston</city>
					<state>VA</state>
					<postal>20192</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>703 648 4543</cntvoice>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc>local time</mettc>
		<metsi>
			<metscs>None</metscs>
			<metsc>Unclassified</metsc>
			<metshd>None</metshd>
		</metsi>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
	</metainfo>
<Esri><PublishedDocID>{EDF8CB0E-762D-4034-992D-E526EBDED65E}</PublishedDocID><PublishStatus>Published</PublishStatus></Esri><mdFileID>{EDF8CB0E-762D-4034-992D-E526EBDED65E}</mdFileID></metadata>