<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <pubdate>20130601</pubdate>
        <title>U.S. Populated Place Points, 2013</title>
        <edition>2013</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>Data &amp; Maps for ArcGIS&#174;</sername>
          <issue>2013 - World, Europe, and United States</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <onlink>http://map.princeton.edu/data/fb/49/4b/11/b/content/restricted/data.zip</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>U.S. Populated Place Points represents populated places that include census designated places, consolidated cities, and incorporated places within United States identified by the U.S. Census Bureau.</abstract>
      <purpose>U.S. Populated Place Points provides locations for populated places including attributes - name, FIPS code, Census class, area, and selected demographic data.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>200004</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>Unknown</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Annually</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-176.645064</westbc>
        <eastbc>173.186142</eastbc>
        <northbc>71.300376</northbc>
        <southbc>19.062918</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>point</themekey>
        <themekey>places</themekey>
        <themekey>populated places</themekey>
        <themekey>cities</themekey>
        <themekey>towns</themekey>
        <themekey>villages</themekey>
        <themekey>demographics</themekey>
        <themekey>housing units</themekey>
        <themekey>location</themekey>
        <themekey>society</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>society</themekey>
        <themekey>location</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>United States</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>2000</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to Esri for inclusion on Data &amp; Maps for ArcGIS&#174; for use with Esri&#174; software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on Data &amp; Maps. As used herein, &#8220;Geodata&#8221; shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this data set: Public domain data from U.S. government is freely redistributable with proper metadata and source attribution.

The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on Data &amp; Maps.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of Esri and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by Esri and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: Esri warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. Esri DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. Esri IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES: 
(A) THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE NOT FAULT-TOLERANT AND ARE NOT DESIGNED, MANUFACTURED, OR INTENDED FOR USE OR RESALE FOR INSURANCE UNDERWRITING OR WITH CRITICAL HEALTH AND SAFETY OR ONLINE CONTROL EQUIPMENT IN HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS THAT REQUIRE FAIL-SAFE PERFORMANCE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE OPERATION OF NUCLEAR FACILITIES, NAVIGATION OR GUIDANCE (I.E., AIRCRAFT, NAUTICAL VEHICLE, ETC.), OR COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS, AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL, EMERGENCY RESPONSE, TERRORISM PREVENTION OR RESPONSE, LIFE SUPPORT, OR WEAPONS SYSTEMS ("HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES"). Esri SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF FITNESS FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES.

(B) TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, LICENSEE AGREES TO INDEMNIFY, DEFEND, AND HOLD Esri, ITS OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUBCONTRACTORS, LICENSORS, SUCCESSORS, AND ASSIGNS HARMLESS FROM AND AGAINST ANY AND ALL LIABILITY, LOSSES, CLAIMS, EXPENSES (INCLUDING ATTORNEYS' FEES), DEMANDS, OR DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH LICENSEE'S USE OR PERMITTING THE USE BY OTHERS OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES. DELIVERY OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE DOES NOT CONSTITUTE A WAIVER OF THE RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS SET FORTH IN THIS ARTICLE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of Esri or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to Esri with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and Esri returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL Esri AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT Esri OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: Esri's licensor(s) has (have) authorized Esri to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the Esri licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to Esri.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, Esri has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</accconst>
    <useconst>See legal constraints.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Esri</cntorg>
          <cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>ArcGIS Content Team</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>us</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
        <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Map and Geospatial Information Center, Lewis Library, Princeton University</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Map and Geospatial Information Center, Lewis Library, Princeton University</address>
          <city>Princeton</city>
          <state>NJ</state>
          <postal>08544</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>609-258-1097</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Esri</cntorg>
          <cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>ArcGIS Content Team</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>us</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
        <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>ESRI</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows 7 Version 6.1 (Build 7601) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS 10.2.0.3348</native>
  </idinfo>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>Entity point</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>25150</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>8.983152841195215e-009</latres>
        <longres>8.983152841195215e-009</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal Degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D WGS 1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS 1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257223563</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>ESRI_2013_places</enttypl>
        <enttypd>The points represent concentrations of population that include census designated places, consolidated cities, and incorporated places identified by the U.S. Census Bureau.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>NAME</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The populated place name.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Names for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CLASS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The class of the populated place.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>borough</edomv>
            <edomvd>In Connecticut, New Jersey, and Pennsylvania, an incorporated place.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</edomvds>
            <edomv>Census Designated Place</edomv>
            <edomvd>Census designated place - A statistical entity, defined for each decennial census according to Census Bureau guidelines, comprising a densely settled concentration of population that is not within an incorporated place, but is locally identified by a name.</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</edomvds>
            <edomv>city</edomv>
            <edomvd>An incorporated place in 49 States and the District of Columbia. In 20 States, some or all cities are not part of any minor civil division, and the Census Bureau also treats these as county subdivisions, statistically equivalent to minor civil divisions.</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</edomvds>
            <edomv>city (consolidated, balance)</edomv>
            <edomvd>The portion of the consolidated city minus the incorporated places. For statistical purposes, these entities are treated as statistically equivalent to a place and have no legal basis or functions.</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>city and borough</edomv>
            <edomvd>unknown</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>city and county</edomv>
            <edomvd>unknown</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomv>municipality</edomv>
            <edomvd>unknown</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</edomvds>
            <edomv>town</edomv>
            <edomvd>An incorporated place in 30 States. In New Jersey, Pennsylvania, and South Dakota, the Census Bureau treats these towns as the equivalent of a minor civil division.</edomvd>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</edomvds>
            <edomv>village</edomv>
            <edomvd>An incorporated place in 20 States. The Census Bureau treats all villages in New Jersey, South Dakota, and Wisconsin, and some villages in Ohio as county subdivisions.</edomvd>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ST</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The two-letter abbreviation for the state in which the populated place is located.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards 5&#8211;2</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STFIPS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The FIPS code (two-digit number) for the state in which the populated place is located.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PLACEFIP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The FIPS code (five-digit number) for the populated place within a State.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, National Institute of Standards and Technology</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <codesetd>
            <codesetn>Federal Information Processing Standards Pub 55</codesetn>
            <codesets>National Institute of Standards and Technology</codesets>
          </codesetd>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>HOUSEUNITS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The 2000 housing unit counts of the populated place.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP2000</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The 2000 population of the populated place.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>POP_CLASS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The code for the population class of the populated place.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <edom>
            <edomv>1</edomv>
            <edomvd>Population from 0 - 249.</edomvd>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
            <edomvd>Population from 250 - 499.</edomvd>
            <edomv>2</edomv>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
            <edomvd>Population from 500 - 999.</edomvd>
            <edomv>3</edomv>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
            <edomvd>Population from 1,000 - 2,499.</edomvd>
            <edomv>4</edomv>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
            <edomvd>Population from 2,500 - 9,999.</edomvd>
            <edomv>5</edomv>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
            <edomvd>Population from 10,000 - 49,999.</edomvd>
            <edomv>6</edomv>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
            <edomvd>Population from 50,000 - 99,999.</edomvd>
            <edomv>7</edomv>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
            <edomvd>Population from 100,000 - 499,999.</edomvd>
            <edomv>8</edomv>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
            <edomvd>Population from 500,000 - 999,999.</edomvd>
            <edomv>9</edomv>
          </edom>
          <edom>
            <edomvds>Esri</edomvds>
            <edomvd>Population from 1,000,000 and up.</edomvd>
            <edomv>10</edomv>
          </edom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREALAND</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The area in square miles of the populated place which is land.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREAWATER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>The area in square miles of the populated place which is water.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Department of Commerce, Census Bureau</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Numbers for the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Esri; Esri Offices</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>us</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>800-447-9778</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
    <distliab>See access and use constraints information.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>SDC Feature Database</formname>
          <transize>1.351</transize>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>http://www.ArcGIS.com</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
          <offoptn>
            <offmedia>dvdRom</offmedia>
          </offoptn>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>Software purchase price. Data &amp; Maps is available only as part of Esri&#174; software. To use this data requires software that supports SDC files.</fees>
      <ordering>Data &amp; Maps is available only as part of Esri&#174; software.

In the United States, contact the Esri Telebusiness staff at 800-447-9778 for more information about our software and data.

Outside the United States, please direct all inquiries to your local Esri Office.  This information can be found at http://www.esri.com/about-esri/offices.</ordering>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20141027</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Esri</cntorg>
          <cntper>ArcGIS Content Team</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntpos>ArcGIS Content Team</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>unknown</addrtype>
          <address>380 New York Street</address>
          <city>Redlands</city>
          <state>California</state>
          <postal>92373-8100</postal>
          <country>us</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>909-793-2853</cntvoice>
        <cntfax>909-793-5953</cntfax>
        <cntemail>info@esri.com</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>