<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Pima County Department of Transportation - Geographic Information Services
          Division</origin>
        <pubdate>20080618</pubdate>
        <title>Pima County, Arizona land parcels, 2008</title>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <onlink>http://map.princeton.edu/data/pr/76/f4/92/7/content/restricted/data.zip</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Land parcels in Pima County, Arizona, 2008.</abstract>
      <purpose>For use with GIS software.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Known Errors/Qualifications: paregion contains duplicate taxcodes for parcels, i.e.
        undeveloped subdivisions in which all lots are assigned the same taxcode, until the lots are
        developed. Users should normalize their analysis results based on the frequency of duplicate
        taxcodes. Reference Scale: 3000 Spatial Domain: Pima County Control: ADOT Rectified: parcel
        Maintenance Organization: PC DOT GIS Division Maintenance Frequency: Daily Maintenance
        Format: Coverage Primary Source Organization: PC DOT GIS Division Primary Source Contact:
        Steve Whitney Primary Source Date: 2006 Primary Source Scale: 200 Primary Source Format: DWG
        Technical Services Contact: Steve Whitney MapGuide Layer Name: Parcels (Landbase) MapGuide
        Scale Range: 0 - 25000</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20080618</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>The date of last update. May not be accurate.</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-113.334221</westbc>
        <eastbc>-110.447680</eastbc>
        <northbc>32.514068</northbc>
        <southbc>31.426106</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>parcels</themekey>
        <themekey>tax parcels</themekey>
        <themekey>land use</themekey>
        <themekey>property maps</themekey>
        <themekey>cadastral maps</themekey>
        <themekey>parcel</themekey>
        <themekey>ownership</themekey>
        <themekey>property</themekey>
        <themekey>tax</themekey>
        <themekey>land value</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Categories</themekt>
        <themekey>planningCadastre</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>Arizona</placekey>
        <placekey>Pima County</placekey>
        <placekey>Tucson</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Public</accconst>
    <useconst>Ownership of Products All information, web pages, data (including digital data), maps,
      programs, software, studies, reports, patents, copyrights and plans obtained by and prepared
      for and by the Pima County Department of Transportation (hereafter "Products") shall
      remain the property of Pima County. It is expressly understood that Pima County (hereafter
      "County") has exclusive control of all information developed for this work. Any
      for-value use of Products shall be retained by the County and negotiated for use by the Pima
      County Department of Transportation. Requestor agrees that any misappropriation or misuse of
      the Products will cause serious damage to the County and that, because money damages may not
      constitute sufficient compensation, any misappropriation or misuse shall justify and allow the
      County to apply to any court having jurisdiction for an injunction or other proper relief and,
      if relief is granted, the County shall be entitled to the reasonable expenses of the action
      including attorney&#65533;s fees. Limitation of Use County Products are provided only for use
      in a computerized records keeping system or for study maps to depict approximate locations.
      Any other use is not authorized by County. Products shall not be copied, reproduced or used in
      any form by any party other than User or an agent of User. Digital data shall not be used by
      any party for any commercial purpose without completing a Verified Statement of Commercial
      Purpose Public Data Request and payment of fees. In addition to other remedies, a violation of
      this limitation of use may result in the assessment of penalties in accordance with A.R.S.
      39-121.03. Products are for illustration purposes only and are not suitable for site-specific
      decision making. Use of Products as an engineering tool is expressly forbidden. Products
      should not be used for making financial or any other commitments. The County provides these
      Products with the understanding that they are not guaranteed to be accurate, correct or
      complete and conclusions drawn from the Products are the responsibility of the User. While
      every effort has been made to ensure the accuracy, correctness and timeliness of materials
      presented anywhere within the Products, the County assumes no responsibility for errors or
      omissions, even if the County is advised of the possibility of such damage. Project
      information is for planning purposes only. The listing of any project by the owner agency does
      not constitute an official commitment by that agency to build the project in the time period
      shown, or at all. The information for any project is subject to change as the project
      development process proceeds over time. Assumption of Risk User understands and acknowledges
      that Products are subject to constant change and accuracy cannot be guaranteed. The County
      gathers information from different sources and agencies. ALL PRODUCTS ARE PROVIDED AS IS, WITH
      ALL FAULTS, AND WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT
      LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.
      County does not warrant that the functions contained in the Products will meet the
      requirements of User or that the operation of Products will be uninterrupted or error free, or
      that defects will be corrected. The entire risk as to the quality, performance and usefulness
      of the Products rests with User. Products may have a number of errors which may include but
      are not limited to the following types of errors: Spatial errors - The areas depicted by these
      Products are approximate, and are not necessarily accurate to surveying or engineering
      standards. X/Y coordinates may be in error by several hundred feet or more. Registration
      errors - Geographic Information System (hereafter "GIS") data layers may not overlay
      each other correctly. Attribute errors - Database information may be incorrect. Currency
      errors - GIS data layers, databases and documents may not be the most current available or may
      not depict the specified time. All data is subject to constant change. Data input lags
      real-world changes by varying periods of time. Completeness errors - Data may be missing or
      data may be included that does not belong. Projection distortion - All map projections
      introduce distortion by representing the irregular shape of the earth's surface on flat maps.
      This affects feature shapes, angles, map distances and areas. We choose projections which
      minimize these distortions when viewing most County maps. Calculation errors - Results of
      calculations may not be exact due to rounding, precision of stored values or algorithm
      differences. Representation errors - Maps or other displays may not properly represent the
      data. For instance, a white line on a white background would appear as if it wasn't there.
      Color coded ("themed") map layers colors and categories may not match the current
      range of data values. Data may be displayed at an inappropriate scale. For example, selecting
      map features on MapGuide maps changes the color of the displayed map features. (Clear selected
      map features to ensure colors match the legend.) Availability Availability of County Internet
      services and Products is not guaranteed. Applications, servers, and network connections may be
      unavailable at any time for maintenance or unscheduled outages. Outages may be of long
      duration. Do not create dependencies on these services for critical needs. Indemnify; Defend;
      Hold Harmless User releases County and their officers, agents, consultants, contractors and
      employees from any and all claims, actions or causes of action for damages including, but not
      limited to, any costs of recovering, reprogramming or reproducing and programs or data stored
      in or used with the Products, damage to property, damages for personal injury or for any lost
      profits, lost savings or other special, incidental or consequential damages arising out of the
      use of or inability to use the Products. User shall indemnify and hold harmless County, its
      officers, agents, consultants, contractors and employees from any and all liability claims or
      damages to any person or property arising from or connected with the use of the Products. THE
      FOREGOING WARRANTY IS EXCLUSIVE AND IN LIEU OF ALL OTHER WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
      FITNESS FOR PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND/OR ANY OTHER TYPE WHETHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED. In no event
      shall the County become liable to Users of these Products or any other party, for any loss or
      direct, indirect, special, incidental or consequential damages, including but not limited to
      time, money or goodwill, arising from the use or modification of the Products. Maintenance of
      Products To assist the County in the maintenance of the Products, Users should provide the
      County information concerning errors or discrepancies found in using the Products. If there is
      an E-mail contact address on affected web page(s), then use it. Otherwise contact: Pima County
      Department of Transportation Geographic Information Services Division 201 N. Stone Ave., 9th
      Floor Tucson, Arizona 85701-1207 Phone: 520-740-6670 Fax: 520-798-3429 E-mail: Acknowledgement
      and Logotype The Pima County Department of Transportation and/or Geographic Information
      Services logotype on the Products shall not be removed or obscured. When logotypes are
      provided with Products, they shall be clearly displayed on all copies or reproductions of the
      Products or parts of the Products. Please acknowledge Pima County as the source when County
      Products are used in the preparation of reports, papers, publications, maps, or other
      products.Data are licensed to Princeton University-affiliated persons only.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pima County Department of Transportation - Geographic Information Services
            Division</cntorg>
          <cntper>Steve Whitney</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>201 N Stone Ave., 9th Floor</address>
          <city>Tucson</city>
          <state>Arizona</state>
          <postal>85701</postal>
          <country>United States of America</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>520-740-6670</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Map and Geospatial Information Center, Lewis Library, Princeton
            University</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>Map and Geospatial Information Center, Lewis Library, Princeton University</address>
          <city>Princeton</city>
          <state>NJ</state>
          <postal>08544</postal>
          <country>US</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>609-258-1097</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <datacred>National ParcelMap Data Portal</datacred>
    <native>Microsoft Windows Vista Version 6.0 (Build 6001) Service Pack 1; Esri ArcGIS
      10.2.0.3348</native>
  </idinfo>
  <Esri>
    <PublishedDocID>{482f41a4-3a3e-4eaf-a298-53002d8caa54}</PublishedDocID>
  </Esri>
  <spdoinfo>
    <direct>Vector</direct>
    <ptvctinf>
      <sdtsterm>
        <sdtstype>GT-polygon composed of chains</sdtstype>
        <ptvctcnt>429677</ptvctcnt>
      </sdtsterm>
    </ptvctinf>
  </spdoinfo>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <latres>8.9831528411952133e-009</latres>
        <longres>8.9831528411952133e-009</longres>
        <geogunit>Decimal Degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D North American 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>GRS 1980</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.0</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>Parcels</enttypl>
      </enttyp>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>EXEMPT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Whether parcel is exempt from property taxes.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>IMPRATIO</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Ratio use in calculation of accessed value.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>APN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Assessors Parcel Number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>APN2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>APN without punctuation and/or another indexing field in GIS.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNTY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>County name.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FIPS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Unique number assigned to county by Census.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SIT_HSE_NU</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>House number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SIT_DIR</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street direction.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SIT_STR_NA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Street name.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SIT_FULL_S</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Full street address.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SIT_CITY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Situs city name.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LAND_VALUE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Assessed land value.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>IMPR_VALUE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Assessed improvement value.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TOT_VALUE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Total assessed value.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>STD_LAND_U</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Standardized land use code.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LOT_SIZE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Lot size or area.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OWNER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Owner name.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OWNER2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Additional owners.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OWNADDRESS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Owner's mailing address.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OWNADDRES2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Additional owner's mailing address.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OWNCTYSTZP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Owner city, state, and ZIP.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Xcoord</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Longitude of point-in-parcel.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Ycoord</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Latitude of point-in-parcel.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>minX</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Longitude of lower left parcel bounding box.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>minY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Latitude of lower left parcel bounding box.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>maxX</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Longitude of upper right parcel bounding box.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>maxY</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Latitude of upper left parcel bounding box.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>NPDP Standard Attribute Table Format</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>IMPSOURCE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Valuation source code.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LANDUNIT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Type of land unit ( A=acres, F= sq.ft., S=site).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Y_HPGN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Y coordinate in the native coordinate system (centroid).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TRACT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Census tract.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PAGE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Recorder's page number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TRS_OL</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Township/Range/Section (overlay derived).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PARCELIDX</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Parcel, map, and book number, first five digits of APN.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>OWNERIDX</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>First five characters of owner name or address.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>TRS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Township/Range/Section.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LANDRATIO</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Ratio use in calculation of accessed value.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CURZONE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Current zoning code.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AUXISTAT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Auxillary status.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MRKT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Market area.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LASTCHANGE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Last change date.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ACRES</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Area in acres.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LEGAL4</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Fourth line of legal description.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LEGAL5</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Former tax code (before split, if any).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LEGAL1</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>First line of legal description.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LANDMEAS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Total number of land units.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FILEID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Parcel's assessment indicator.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>MP</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Map and plot number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LEGAL3</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Third line of legal description.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LOT</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Subdivision lot number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>SECTMODIF</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Section modifier (parcel crosses section lines).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>COUNTYCODE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>State of Arizona county code.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PAREGION_I</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stump</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LANDCLASS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Revised land use code.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>BLOCK</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Subdivision block number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>AREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stump</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PRIORLMTD</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Prior limited assessment value.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LOT_R</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Same as field LOT with leadings zeros removed.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PAREGION_</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stump</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>FID</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
        <attrdomv>
          <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
        </attrdomv>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>IMPCLASS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Improvement legislative class.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>DOCKET</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Recorder's docket number.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>PERIMETER</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Stump</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>CENSUS</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Census tract 1990.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>X_HPGN</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>X coordinate in the native coordinate system (centroid).</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>LEGAL2</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Second line of legal description.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>GROUPCODE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Tax group code.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>ASRAREA</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Tax area.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
      <attr>
        <attrlabl>RECORDDATE</attrlabl>
        <attrdef>Recording date.</attrdef>
        <attrdefs>Pima County Department of Transportation</attrdefs>
      </attr>
    </detailed>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20140324</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Pima County Department of Transportation - Geographic Information Services
            Division</cntorg>
          <cntper>Metadata Librarian</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
          <address>201 N Stone Ave., 9th Floor</address>
          <city>Tucson</city>
          <state>Arizona</state>
          <postal>85701</postal>
          <country>United States of America</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>520-740-6670</cntvoice>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metuc>Data are licensed to Princeton University-affiliated persons only.</metuc>
    <metsi>
      <metsc>Unclassified</metsc>
    </metsi>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>