<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</origin>
        <pubdate>19990801</pubdate>
        <title>World Rivers 1999</title>
        <edition>1999</edition>
        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
        <serinfo>
          <sername>ESRI Data &amp; Maps</sername>
          <issue>1999</issue>
        </serinfo>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
          <publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>http://map.princeton.edu/data/d5/04/rn/01/v/content/restricted/data.zip</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>World Rivers represents the major rivers within the world.</abstract>
      <purpose>World Rivers provides a base map layer of major rivers of the world.</purpose>
      <supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:15,000,000.</supplinf>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <mdattim>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>19920801</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>1991</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>1990</caldate>
          </sngdate>
          <sngdate>
            <caldate>1992</caldate>
          </sngdate>
        </mdattim>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>publication date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>Complete</progress>
      <update>Matches software update releases</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-164.624557</westbc>
        <eastbc>161.065826</eastbc>
        <northbc>72.234184</northbc>
        <southbc>-36.904354</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>line</themekey>
        <themekey>rivers</themekey>
        <themekey>drainage</themekey>
        <themekey>drainage systems</themekey>
        <themekey>hydrography</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>World</placekey>
      </place>
      <temporal>
        <tempkt>None</tempkt>
        <tempkey>1992</tempkey>
        <tempkey>1991</tempkey>
        <tempkey>1990</tempkey>
        <tempkey>1992</tempkey>
      </temporal>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
    <useconst>The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps CD&#8211;ROMs for use with ESRI&#174; software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps CD&#8211;ROMs. As used herein, &#8220;Geodata&#8221; shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.The redistribution rights for this data set: Redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor for hard-copy renditions or static, electronic map images (e.g. .gif, .jpeg, etc.) that are plotted, printed, or publicly displayed with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s). Geodata is redistributable with a Value-Added Software Application developed by ESRI Business Partners on a royalty-free basis with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s). Geodata is redistributable without a Value-Added Software Application (i.e., adding the sample data to an existing, [non]commercial data set for redistribution) with proper metadata and source/copyright attribution to the respective data vendor(s).The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on the ESRI Data &amp; Maps CD&#8211;ROMs.Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and t</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Princeton University Library</cntorg>
          <cntper>Tsering Wangyal Shawa</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>609-258-6804</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>shawatw@princeton.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>8:45 a.m.&#8211;5:00 p.m. EST, Monday&#8211;Friday</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Version 6.0 (Build 6000) ; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.4.1420</native>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <logic>No duplicate features are present.  The shapefile is exported using Avenue request ExportClean.  This request verifies and enforces the correctness of shapes.</logic>
    <complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The geospatial part of this data set was extracted from the ArcWorld 1:25M and 1:3M databases and then generalized (tolerance unknown).  The positional accuracy is unknown.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</origin>
            <pubdate>19920801</pubdate>
            <title>ArcWorld 1:3M, ArcWorld 1:25M</title>
            <edition>1</edition>
            <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>CD&#8211;ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>19920801</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>ArcWorld 1:3M, 1:25M</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Rand McNally &amp; Company</origin>
            <pubdate>1991</pubdate>
            <title>Rand McNally New International Atlas</title>
            <edition>2nd printing, revised</edition>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>Rand McNally New International Atlas</sername>
              <issue>2nd printing, revised</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Chicago, Illinois, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>Rand McNally &amp; Company</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1991</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Rand McNally Int.</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Bartholemew and Times Books</origin>
            <pubdate>1990</pubdate>
            <title>The Times Atlas of the World</title>
            <edition>8th comprehensive edition</edition>
            <serinfo>
              <sername>The Times Atlas of the World</sername>
              <issue>8th comprehensive edition</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Edinburgh, Scotland</pubplace>
              <publish>Bartholemew and Times Books</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>paper</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1990</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>Times Atlas</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</origin>
            <origin>Defense Mapping Agency, presently known as National Imagery and Mapping Agency</origin>
            <pubdate>1992</pubdate>
            <title>Digital Chart of the World</title>
            <edition>1</edition>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
              <publish>Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc. (ESRI)</publish>
            </pubinfo>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <typesrc>CD&#8211;ROM</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>1992</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>DCW</srccitea>
        <srccontr>Attribute data</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The following steps were performed by ESRI: Extracted the features from ArcWorld 1:25M.  Aligned the mouths of rivers with coastlines. Made features consistent with all political boundaries they are coincident with.  Added attribute values from the Rand McNally New International Atlas, the Times Atlas of the World, the Digital Chart of the World, and World Resources Institute.  Added St. Lawrence system from ArcWorld 1:3M.  Generalized to match detail of the Cntry98.shp. Removed unneeded attributes. Created ArcGIS&#8482; layer file (.lyr).  Created ArcView legend file (.avl).  Created projection file (.prj).  Ran ArcView Avenue request ExportClean, and created spatial indices.</procdesc>
        <srcused>ArcWorld 1:3M, ArcWorld 1:25M</srcused>
        <srcused>Rand McNally Int.</srcused>
        <srcused>Times Atlas</srcused>
        <srcused>DCW</srcused>
        <procdate>19990103</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <geograph>
        <geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
      </geograph>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
        <ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257224</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
  </spref>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
        </cntaddr>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20081113</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Princeton University Library</cntorg>
          <cntper>Tsering Wangyal Shawa</cntper>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
          <address>Digital Map and Geospatial Information Center, The Lewis Library, Room 228, Princeton University</address>
          <city>Princeton</city>
          <state>NJ</state>
          <postal>08544</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>609-258-6804</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>shawatw@princeton.edu</cntemail>
        <hours>8:45 a.m.&#8211;5:00 p.m. EST, Monday&#8211;Friday</hours>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
      <metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
<Esri><PublishedDocID>{C9CEF3A6-A5CA-4945-BDFC-179F38E911E4}</PublishedDocID><PublishStatus>Published</PublishStatus></Esri><mdFileID>{C9CEF3A6-A5CA-4945-BDFC-179F38E911E4}</mdFileID></metadata>