<metadata xml:lang="en">
   <Esri>
      <CreaDate>20081006</CreaDate>
      <CreaTime>13180900</CreaTime>
      <SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce>
      <SyncDate>20040115</SyncDate>
      <SyncTime>20512200</SyncTime>
      <ModDate>20081006</ModDate>
      <ModTime>13165100</ModTime>
      <Sync>FALSE</Sync>
      <MetaID>{8AA1B635-9DA1-4303-8967-5B432430F4C7}</MetaID>
      <PublishedDocID>{4FF9D606-377F-44CC-94B2-9278B51450CB}</PublishedDocID>
      <PublishStatus>Published</PublishStatus>
   </Esri>
   <idinfo>
      <native Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.3.0.800</native>
      <descript>
         <langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata>
         <abstract>World Wildlife Fund Marine Ecoregions represents global marine ecoregions. Ecoregions are defined as relatively large areas of land or water in the world containing a characteristic set of natural communities that share a large majority of their species, dynamics, and environmental conditions. This data set contains the marine ecoregions of the Global 200. Global 200 ecoregions are a collection of the Earth's most outstanding and diverse terrestrial, freshwater, and marine habitats where the Earth's biological wealth is most distinctive and rich, where its loss will be most severely felt, and we must protect if we are to preserve the web of life. For more information, contact http://www.worldwildlife.org.</abstract>
         <purpose>World Wildlife Fund Marine Ecoregions provides a global view of marine ecoregions defined by the World Wildlife Fund Conservation Science Program 2001, and can be used for geographic display.</purpose>
         <supplinf>Largest scale when displaying the data: 1:50,000,000.</supplinf>
      </descript>
      <citation>
         <citeinfo>
            <pubdate>20080401</pubdate>
            <title>World Wildlife Fund Marine Ecoregions 2008</title>
            <ftname Sync="TRUE">wwf_mar.sdc</ftname>
            <geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform>
            <edition>2008</edition>
            <serinfo>
               <sername>ESRI&#174; Data &amp; Maps</sername>
               <issue>2008 World, Europe, United States, Canada, and Mexico</issue>
            </serinfo>
            <pubinfo>
               <pubplace>Redlands, California, USA</pubplace>
               <publish>ESRI</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <origin>World Wildlife Fund</origin>
            <origin>ESRI</origin>
            <onlink>http://map.princeton.edu/data/xk/81/jm/89/0/content/restricted/data.zip</onlink>
         </citeinfo>
      </citation>
      <timeperd>
         <current>publication date</current>
         <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
               <caldate>2001</caldate>
            </sngdate>
         </timeinfo>
      </timeperd>
      <status>
         <progress>Complete</progress>
         <update>Annually</update>
      </status>
      <spdom>
         <bounding>
            <westbc Sync="TRUE">-179.999955</westbc>
            <eastbc Sync="TRUE">179.999964</eastbc>
            <northbc Sync="TRUE">82.806018</northbc>
            <southbc Sync="TRUE">-85.855218</southbc>
         </bounding>
         <lboundng>
            <leftbc Sync="TRUE">-179.999955</leftbc>
            <rightbc Sync="TRUE">179.999964</rightbc>
            <bottombc Sync="TRUE">-85.855218</bottombc>
            <topbc Sync="TRUE">82.806018</topbc>
         </lboundng>
      </spdom>
      <keywords>
         <theme>
            <themekt>None</themekt>
            <themekey>polygon</themekey>
            <themekey>ecoregions</themekey>
            <themekey>ecosystems</themekey>
            <themekey>species richness</themekey>
            <themekey>species endemism</themekey>
            <themekey>ecological</themekey>
            <themekey>evolutionary</themekey>
            <themekey>habitat</themekey>
            <themekey>global rarity</themekey>
            <themekey>biodiversity</themekey>
            <themekey>global 200</themekey>
            <themekey>oceans</themekey>
            <themekey>biota</themekey>
         </theme>
         <place>
            <placekey>World</placekey>
            <placekt>None</placekt>
         </place>
         <temporal>
            <tempkey>2001</tempkey>
            <tempkt>None</tempkt>
         </temporal>
      </keywords>
      <accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
      <useconst>The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps for use with ESRI&#174; software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps. As used herein, &#8220;Geodata&#8221; shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this data set: Internal Use Only. No redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor and the data is for the end user's own internal use only.

Special notice from World Wildlife Fund for this data set: Any modification of the original map by users to ecoregion boundaries, units, names, or biome classes must be noted.

The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES: 
(A) THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE NOT FAULT-TOLERANT AND ARE NOT DESIGNED, MANUFACTURED, OR INTENDED FOR USE OR RESALE FOR INSURANCE UNDERWRITING OR WITH CRITICAL HEALTH AND SAFETY OR ONLINE CONTROL EQUIPMENT IN HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS THAT REQUIRE FAIL-SAFE PERFORMANCE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE OPERATION OF NUCLEAR FACILITIES, NAVIGATION OR GUIDANCE (I.E., AIRCRAFT, NAUTICAL VEHICLE, ETC.), OR COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS, AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL, EMERGENCY RESPONSE, TERRORISM PREVENTION OR RESPONSE, LIFE SUPPORT, OR WEAPONS SYSTEMS ("HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES"). ESRI SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF FITNESS FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES.

(B) TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, LICENSEE AGREES TO INDEMNIFY, DEFEND, AND HOLD ESRI, ITS OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUBCONTRACTORS, LICENSORS, SUCCESSORS, AND ASSIGNS HARMLESS FROM AND AGAINST ANY AND ALL LIABILITY, LOSSES, CLAIMS, EXPENSES (INCLUDING ATTORNEYS' FEES), DEMANDS, OR DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH LICENSEE'S USE OR PERMITTING THE USE BY OTHERS OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES. DELIVERY OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE DOES NOT CONSTITUTE A WAIVER OF THE RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS SET FORTH IN THIS ARTICLE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</useconst>
      <natvform>shapefile</natvform>
      <ptcontac>
         <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
               <cntorg>Princeton University Library</cntorg>
               <cntper>Tsering Wangyal Shawa</cntper>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
               <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
               <city>Princeton </city>
               <state>New Jersey</state>
               <postal>08544</postal>
               <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>609-258-6804</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>shawatw@princeton.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>8:45 a.m.&#8211;5:00 p.m. EST, Monday&#8211;Friday</hours>
         </cntinfo>
      </ptcontac>
   </idinfo>
   <metainfo>
      <langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta>
      <metstdn Sync="TRUE">FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
      <metstdv Sync="TRUE">FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
      <mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc>
      <metc>
         <cntinfo>
            <cntorgp>
               <cntper>Tsering Wangyal Shawa</cntper>
               <cntorg>Princeton University Library</cntorg>
            </cntorgp>
            <cntaddr>
               <addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
               <city>Princeton</city>
               <state>New Jersey</state>
               <postal>08544</postal>
               <country>USA</country>
            </cntaddr>
            <cntvoice>609-258-6804</cntvoice>
            <cntemail>shawatw@princeton.edu</cntemail>
            <hours>8:45 a.m.&#8211;5:00 p.m. EST, Monday&#8211;Friday</hours>
         </cntinfo>
      </metc>
      <metd Sync="TRUE">20081006</metd>
      <metextns>
         <onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
         <metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
      </metextns>
   </metainfo>
   <spdoinfo>
      <direct Sync="TRUE">Vector</direct>
      <ptvctinf>
         <esriterm Name="wwf_mar">
            <efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp>
            <efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polygon</efeageom>
            <esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo>
            <efeacnt Sync="TRUE">43</efeacnt>
            <spindex>TRUE</spindex>
            <linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer>
            <featdesc>World Wildlife Fund Marine Ecoregion</featdesc>
         </esriterm>
         <sdtsterm Name="wwf_mar">
            <sdtstype Sync="TRUE">G-polygon</sdtstype>
            <ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">43</ptvctcnt>
         </sdtsterm>
      </ptvctinf>
   </spdoinfo>
   <spref>
      <horizsys>
         <cordsysn>
            <geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_WGS_1984</geogcsn>
         </cordsysn>
         <geograph>
            <geogunit Sync="TRUE">Decimal degrees</geogunit>
            <latres Sync="TRUE">0.000009</latres>
            <longres Sync="TRUE">0.000009</longres>
         </geograph>
         <geodetic>
            <horizdn Sync="TRUE">D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
            <ellips Sync="TRUE">WGS_1984</ellips>
            <semiaxis Sync="TRUE">6378137.000000</semiaxis>
            <denflat Sync="TRUE">298.257224</denflat>
         </geodetic>
      </horizsys>
   </spref>
   <eainfo>
      <detailed Name="wwf_mar">
         <enttyp>
            <enttypl Sync="TRUE">wwf_mar</enttypl>
            <enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt>
            <enttypc Sync="TRUE">43</enttypc>
            <enttypd>The polygons represent global marine ecoregions defined as relatively large areas of water in the world that share a large majority of their species, dynamics, and environmental conditions.</enttypd>
            <enttypds>World Wildlife Fund</enttypds>
         </enttyp>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">ObjectID</attrlabl>
            <attalias Sync="TRUE">ObjectID</attalias>
            <attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype>
            <attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth>
            <atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis>
            <attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale>
            <attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">Shape</attrlabl>
            <attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias>
            <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype>
            <attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth>
            <atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis>
            <attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale>
            <attrdef Sync="TRUE">Feature geometry.</attrdef>
            <attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs>
            <attrdomv>
               <udom Sync="TRUE">Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
            </attrdomv>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">G200_REGIO</attrlabl>
            <attalias Sync="TRUE">G200_REGIO</attalias>
            <attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype>
            <attwidth Sync="TRUE">35</attwidth>
            <attrdefs>World Wildlife Fund</attrdefs>
            <attrdef>The name of the Global 200 ecoregion that this ecoregion is a part of. If there is no name the ecoregion is not a Global 200 ecoregion.</attrdef>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>(blank)</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Not a Global 200 Region.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomvds>World Wildlife Fund</edomvds>
                  <edomv>Name</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Names for the features.</edomvd>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
            <atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis>
            <attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">G200_BIOME</attrlabl>
            <attalias Sync="TRUE">G200_BIOME</attalias>
            <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype>
            <attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth>
            <attrdefs>World Wildlife Fund</attrdefs>
            <attrdef>The biome of the Global 200 region that the ecoregion is a component of. Occasionally a Global 200 region is made up of ecoregions of different biomes. In this case, for a particular ecoregion, the G200_BIOME may be different from the original biome.</attrdef>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>
                  <edomv>0</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Not a Global 200 Biome.</edomvd>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomvds>World Wildlife Fund</edomvds>
                  <edomv>22</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Polar.</edomvd>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomvds>World Wildlife Fund</edomvds>
                  <edomv>23</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Temperate Shelf and Seas.</edomvd>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomvds>World Wildlife Fund</edomvds>
                  <edomv>24</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Temperate Upwelling.</edomvd>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomvds>World Wildlife Fund</edomvds>
                  <edomv>25</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Tropical Upwelling.</edomvd>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomvds>World Wildlife Fund</edomvds>
                  <edomv>26</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Tropical Coral.</edomvd>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
            <atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis>
            <attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale>
         </attr>
         <attr>
            <attrlabl Sync="TRUE">G200_NUM</attrlabl>
            <attalias Sync="TRUE">G200_NUM</attalias>
            <attrtype Sync="TRUE">Integer</attrtype>
            <attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth>
            <attrdefs>World Wildlife Fund</attrdefs>
            <attrdef>The unique number identifying Global 200 ecoregions.</attrdef>
            <attrdomv>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>0</edomv>
                  <edomvd>Not a Global 200 Number.</edomvd>
                  <edomvds>ESRI</edomvds>
               </edom>
               <edom>
                  <edomv>Number</edomv>
                  <edomvds>World Wildlife Fund</edomvds>
                  <edomvd>Unique numbers for the features.</edomvd>
               </edom>
            </attrdomv>
            <atprecis Sync="TRUE">10</atprecis>
            <attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale>
         </attr>
      </detailed>
   </eainfo>
   <dataqual>
      <lineage>
         <srcinfo>
            <srccite>
               <citeinfo>
                  <title>World Wildlife Fund Conservation Science Program 2001</title>
                  <origin>World Wildlife Fund </origin>
                  <pubdate>2001</pubdate>
                  <edition>2001</edition>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <pubinfo>
                     <publish>World Wildlife Fund</publish>
                     <pubplace>Washington, DC, USA</pubplace>
                  </pubinfo>
                  <othercit>Cited in reference sections, on maps, or on databases with the full citation: Olson, D.M., E. Dinerstein, E.D. Wikramanayake, N.D. Burgess, G.V.N. Powell, E.C. Underwood, J.A. D'Amico, H.E. Strand, J.C. Morrison, C.J. Loucks, T.F. Allnutt, J.F. Lamoreux, T.H. Ricketts, I. Itoua, W.W. Wettengel, Y. Kura, P. Hedao, and K. Kassem. 2001. Terrestrial ecoregions of the world: A new map of life on Earth. BioScience 51(11):933-938.

Sherman, K. and T. Laughlin. 1992. The large marine ecosystem (LME) concept and its application to regional marine resources management. Marine Conservation Development Reports, Gland, Switzerland.</othercit>
               </citeinfo>
            </srccite>
            <typesrc>online</typesrc>
            <srctime>
               <timeinfo>
                  <sngdate>
                     <caldate>2001</caldate>
                  </sngdate>
               </timeinfo>
               <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
            </srctime>
            <srccitea>World Wildlife Fund</srccitea>
            <srccontr>Attribute and geospatial data</srccontr>
         </srcinfo>
         <procstep>
            <procdesc>We began by accepting the biogeographic realms of Pielou (1979) and Udvardy (1975) and modifying the biome systems of Dinerstein et al. (1995) and Ricketts et al. (1999). We then consulted existing global maps of floristic or zoogeographic provinces, global and regional maps of units based on the distribution of selected groups of plants and animals, the world's biotic province maps, and global maps of broad vegetation types. These were useful for evaluating the extent of realms and biomes, the first two tiers in our hierarchical classification. 

We then identified published regional classification systems to be used as a baseline for ecoregion boundaries. Data and consultations from regional experts were also important for final ecoregion delineations.</procdesc>
            <srcprod>World Wildlife Fund</srcprod>
            <procdate>2001</procdate>
            <procsv>ArcView&#174; GIS 3</procsv>
         </procstep>
      </lineage>
      <posacc>
         <horizpa>
            <horizpar>The positional accuracy is not known.</horizpar>
         </horizpa>
      </posacc>
      <logic>The shapefile is converted to SDC (Smart Data Compression) format using either ESRI SDC Data Development Kit Professional 2 (DDKP2) or tools in ArcGIS.  The SDC data set is then loaded into ArcSDE&#174; to verify and validate the geometry.</logic>
      <complete>After processing, the data set is checked for drawing display and number of records and file sizes compared with source materials.</complete>
   </dataqual>
   <dataIdInfo>
      <envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows 2000 Version 5.0 (Build 2195) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 8.3.0.800</envirDesc>
      <dataLang>
         <languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en" />
      </dataLang>
      <idCitation>
         <resTitle>World Wildlife Fund Marine Ecoregions</resTitle>
         <presForm>
            <PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005" />
         </presForm>
         <resEd>2008</resEd>
         <resEdDate>20080401</resEdDate>
         <resRefDate>
            <refDate>20021017</refDate>
            <refDateType>
               <DateTypCd value="001" />
            </refDateType>
         </resRefDate>
         <citRespParty>
            <rpIndName>Data Team</rpIndName>
            <rpOrgName>ESRI</rpOrgName>
            <rpPosName>Data Team</rpPosName>
            <role>
               <RoleCd value="007" />
            </role>
            <rpCntInfo>
               <cntAddress>
                  <delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint>
                  <city>Redlands</city>
                  <adminArea>California</adminArea>
                  <postCode>92373-8100</postCode>
                  <eMailAdd>info@esri.com</eMailAdd>
                  <country>us</country>
               </cntAddress>
               <cntPhone>
                  <voiceNum>909-793-2853</voiceNum>
                  <faxNum>909-793-5953</faxNum>
               </cntPhone>
            </rpCntInfo>
         </citRespParty>
         <citRespParty>
            <rpOrgName>World Wildlife Fund</rpOrgName>
            <rpCntInfo>
               <cntAddress>
                  <city>Washington</city>
                  <adminArea>District of Columbia</adminArea>
                  <country>us</country>
               </cntAddress>
            </rpCntInfo>
            <role>
               <RoleCd value="006" />
            </role>
         </citRespParty>
         <resRefDate>
            <refDate>20080401</refDate>
            <refDateType>
               <DateTypCd value="002" />
            </refDateType>
         </resRefDate>
      </idCitation>
      <spatRpType>
         <SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" />
      </spatRpType>
      <dataExt>
         <geoEle>
            <GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native">
               <westBL Sync="TRUE">-179.999955</westBL>
               <eastBL Sync="TRUE">179.999964</eastBL>
               <northBL Sync="TRUE">82.806018</northBL>
               <southBL Sync="TRUE">-85.855218</southBL>
               <exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode>
            </GeoBndBox>
         </geoEle>
         <tempEle>
            <TempExtent>
               <exTemp>
                  <TM_GeometricPrimitive>
                     <TM_Instant>
                        <tmPosition>
                           <TM_CalDate>
                              <calDate>2001</calDate>
                           </TM_CalDate>
                        </tmPosition>
                     </TM_Instant>
                  </TM_GeometricPrimitive>
               </exTemp>
            </TempExtent>
         </tempEle>
      </dataExt>
      <geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees">
         <westBL Sync="TRUE">-179.999955</westBL>
         <eastBL Sync="TRUE">179.999964</eastBL>
         <northBL Sync="TRUE">82.806018</northBL>
         <southBL Sync="TRUE">-85.855218</southBL>
         <exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode>
      </geoBox>
      <idAbs>World Wildlife Fund Marine Ecoregions represents global marine ecoregions. Ecoregions are defined as relatively large areas of land or water in the world containing a characteristic set of natural communities that share a large majority of their species, dynamics, and environmental conditions. This data set contains the marine ecoregions of the Global 200. Global 200 ecoregions are a collection of the Earth's most outstanding and diverse terrestrial, freshwater, and marine habitats where the Earth's biological wealth is most distinctive and rich, where its loss will be most severely felt, and we must protect if we are to preserve the web of life. For more information, contact http://www.worldwildlife.org.</idAbs>
      <resConst>
         <Consts>
            <useLimit>See legal constraints.</useLimit>
         </Consts>
         <LegConsts>
            <accessConsts>
               <RestrictCd value="005" />
            </accessConsts>
            <othConsts>The data are provided by multiple, third party data vendors under license to ESRI for inclusion on ESRI Data &amp; Maps for use with ESRI&#174; software.  Each data vendor has its own data licensing policies and may grant varying redistribution rights to end users. Please consult the redistribution rights below for this data set provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps. As used herein, &#8220;Geodata&#8221; shall mean any digital data set consisting of geographic data coordinates and associated attributes.

The redistribution rights for this data set: Internal Use Only. No redistribution rights are granted by the data vendor and the data is for the end user's own internal use only.

Special notice from World Wildlife Fund for this data set: Any modification of the original map by users to ecoregion boundaries, units, names, or biome classes must be noted.

The terms and conditions below apply to all the data sets provided on ESRI Data &amp; Maps.

Proprietary Rights and Copyright: Licensee acknowledges that the Data and Related Materials contain proprietary and confidential property of ESRI and its licensor(s). The Data and Related Materials are owned by ESRI and its licensor(s) and are protected by United States copyright laws and applicable international copyright treaties and/or conventions.

Limited Warranty and Disclaimer: ESRI warrants that the media upon which the Data and Related Materials are provided will be free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service for a period of ninety (90) days from the date of receipt.

THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE EXCLUDED FROM THE LIMITED WARRANTY, AND THE LICENSEE EXPRESSLY ACKNOWLEDGES THAT THE DATA CONTAINS SOME NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS. ESRI DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THE DATA WILL MEET LICENSEE'S NEEDS OR EXPECTATIONS; THAT THE USE OF THE DATA WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED; OR THAT ALL NONCONFORMITIES, DEFECTS, OR ERRORS CAN OR WILL BE CORRECTED. ESRI IS NOT INVITING RELIANCE ON THIS DATA, AND THE LICENSEE SHOULD ALWAYS VERIFY ACTUAL DATA.

EXCEPT FOR THE LIMITED WARRANTY SET FORTH ABOVE, THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS CONTAINED THEREIN ARE PROVIDED "AS-IS," WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.

HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES: 
(A) THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS ARE NOT FAULT-TOLERANT AND ARE NOT DESIGNED, MANUFACTURED, OR INTENDED FOR USE OR RESALE FOR INSURANCE UNDERWRITING OR WITH CRITICAL HEALTH AND SAFETY OR ONLINE CONTROL EQUIPMENT IN HAZARDOUS ENVIRONMENTS THAT REQUIRE FAIL-SAFE PERFORMANCE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE OPERATION OF NUCLEAR FACILITIES, NAVIGATION OR GUIDANCE (I.E., AIRCRAFT, NAUTICAL VEHICLE, ETC.), OR COMMUNICATION SYSTEMS, AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL, EMERGENCY RESPONSE, TERRORISM PREVENTION OR RESPONSE, LIFE SUPPORT, OR WEAPONS SYSTEMS ("HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES"). ESRI SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTY OF FITNESS FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES.

(B) TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY LAW, LICENSEE AGREES TO INDEMNIFY, DEFEND, AND HOLD ESRI, ITS OFFICERS, DIRECTORS, EMPLOYEES, AGENTS, SUBCONTRACTORS, LICENSORS, SUCCESSORS, AND ASSIGNS HARMLESS FROM AND AGAINST ANY AND ALL LIABILITY, LOSSES, CLAIMS, EXPENSES (INCLUDING ATTORNEYS' FEES), DEMANDS, OR DAMAGES OF ANY KIND, INCLUDING DIRECT, INDIRECT, SPECIAL, PUNITIVE, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, ARISING OUT OF OR IN ANY WAY CONNECTED WITH LICENSEE'S USE OR PERMITTING THE USE BY OTHERS OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE FOR HIGH RISK ACTIVITIES. DELIVERY OF THE DATA, AND VENDOR'S HARDWARE OR SOFTWARE DOES NOT CONSTITUTE A WAIVER OF THE RIGHTS AND OBLIGATIONS SET FORTH IN THIS ARTICLE.

Exclusive Remedy and Limitation of Liability: The entire liability of ESRI or its licensor(s) and Licensee's exclusive remedy shall be to terminate the Agreement upon Licensee returning the Data and Related Materials to ESRI with a copy of Licensee's invoice/receipt and ESRI returning the license fees paid to Licensee.

IN NO EVENT SHALL ESRI AND/OR ITS LICENSOR(S) BE LIABLE FOR COSTS OF PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOST PROFITS, LOST SALES, OR BUSINESS EXPENDITURES, INVESTMENTS, OR COMMITMENTS IN CONNECTION WITH ANY BUSINESS; LOSS OF ANY GOODWILL; OR FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING OUT OF THIS AGREEMENT OR USE OF THE DATA AND RELATED MATERIALS, HOWEVER CAUSED, ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, AND WHETHER OR NOT ESRI OR ITS LICENSOR(S) HAVE BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE. THESE LIMITATIONS SHALL APPLY NOTWITHSTANDING ANY FAILURE OF ESSENTIAL PURPOSE OF ANY EXCLUSIVE REMEDY.

Third Party Beneficiary: ESRI's licensor(s) has (have) authorized ESRI to (sub)distribute and (sub)license its (their) data as incorporated into the Data and Related Materials. As an intended third party beneficiary to this Agreement, the ESRI licensor(s) is (are) entitled to directly enforce, in its own name, the rights and obligations undertaken by the Licensee and to seek all legal and equitable remedies as are afforded to ESRI.

In the event that the data vendor(s) has (have) granted the end user permission to redistribute the Geodata, please use proper proprietary or copyright attribution for the various data vendor(s), and provide the associated metadata file(s) with the Geodata. In compliance with FGDC metadata standards, ESRI has attempted to practice proper metadata methodologies by providing any data source information, descriptions, and file names to assist in this effort.</othConsts>
            <useConsts>
               <RestrictCd value="008" />
            </useConsts>
         </LegConsts>
      </resConst>
      <dataScale>
         <equScale>
            <rfDenom>50000000</rfDenom>
         </equScale>
      </dataScale>
      <descKeys KeyTypCd="005">
         <keyTyp>
            <KeyTypCd value="005" />
         </keyTyp>
         <keyword>polygon, ecoregions, ecosystems, species richness, species endemism, ecological, evolutionary, habitat, global rarity, biodiversity, global 200, oceans, biota</keyword>
      </descKeys>
      <descKeys KeyTypCd="002">
         <keyTyp>
            <KeyTypCd value="002" />
         </keyTyp>
         <keyword>World</keyword>
      </descKeys>
      <descKeys KeyTypCd="004">
         <keyTyp>
            <KeyTypCd value="004" />
         </keyTyp>
         <keyword>2001</keyword>
      </descKeys>
      <tpCat>
         <TopicCatCd value="002" />
      </tpCat>
      <tpCat>
         <TopicCatCd value="007" />
      </tpCat>
      <tpCat>
         <TopicCatCd value="014" />
      </tpCat>
      <resMaint>
         <maintFreq>
            <MaintFreqCd value="008" />
         </maintFreq>
      </resMaint>
   </dataIdInfo>
   <mdLang>
      <languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en" />
   </mdLang>
   <mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName>
   <mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer>
   <mdChar>
      <CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="005" />
   </mdChar>
   <mdHrLv>
      <ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005" />
   </mdHrLv>
   <mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName>
   <distInfo>
      <distributor>
         <distorTran>
            <onLineSrc>
               <orDesc>003</orDesc>
               <linkage Sync="TRUE">file://</linkage>
               <protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol>
            </onLineSrc>
            <transSize Sync="TRUE">0.020</transSize>
            <offLineMed>
               <medName>
                  <MedNameCd value="003" />
               </medName>
            </offLineMed>
         </distorTran>
         <distorFormat>
            <formatName Sync="TRUE">SDC Feature Database</formatName>
         </distorFormat>
         <distorCont>
            <rpOrgName>ESRI; ESRI International Distributors</rpOrgName>
            <rpCntInfo>
               <cntAddress>
                  <delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint>
                  <city>Redlands</city>
                  <adminArea>California</adminArea>
                  <postCode>92373-8100</postCode>
                  <country>us</country>
               </cntAddress>
               <cntPhone>
                  <voiceNum>800-447-9778</voiceNum>
               </cntPhone>
            </rpCntInfo>
            <role>
               <RoleCd value="005" />
            </role>
         </distorCont>
         <distorOrdPrc>
            <ordInstr>ESRI Data &amp; Maps is available only as part of ESRI&#174; software.

In the United States, contact the ESRI Telebusiness staff at 800-447-9778 for more information about our software and data.

Outside the United States, please direct all inquiries to your local ESRI International Distributor.  This information can be found at http://gis.esri.com/intldist/contact/.</ordInstr>
            <resFees>Software purchase price. ESRI Data &amp; Maps is available only as part of ESRI&#174; software. To use this data requires software that supports SDC files.</resFees>
         </distorOrdPrc>
      </distributor>
   </distInfo>
   <refSysInfo>
      <RefSystem>
         <refSysID>
            <identCode Sync="TRUE">GCS_WGS_1984</identCode>
         </refSysID>
      </RefSystem>
   </refSysInfo>
   <spatRepInfo>
      <VectSpatRep>
         <topLvl>
            <TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" />
         </topLvl>
         <geometObjs Name="wwf_mar">
            <geoObjTyp>
               <GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001" />
            </geoObjTyp>
            <geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">43</geoObjCnt>
         </geometObjs>
      </VectSpatRep>
   </spatRepInfo>
   <mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20081006</mdDateSt>
   <Binary>
      <Thumbnail />
   </Binary>
   <mdContact>
      <rpIndName>Data Team</rpIndName>
      <rpOrgName>ESRI</rpOrgName>
      <rpPosName>Data Team</rpPosName>
      <rpCntInfo>
         <cntAddress>
            <delPoint>380 New York Street</delPoint>
            <city>Redlands</city>
            <adminArea>California</adminArea>
            <postCode>92373-8100</postCode>
            <eMailAdd>info@esri.com</eMailAdd>
            <country>us</country>
         </cntAddress>
         <cntPhone>
            <voiceNum>909-793-2853</voiceNum>
            <faxNum>909-793-5953</faxNum>
         </cntPhone>
      </rpCntInfo>
      <role>
         <RoleCd value="010" />
      </role>
   </mdContact>
   <dqInfo>
      <dataLineage>
         <statement>World Wildlife Fund (source 1 of 1) 

World Wildlife Fund, 2001, World Wildlife Fund Conservation Science Program 2001: World Wildlife Fund, Washington, DC, USA. 

Other citation details: 
Cited in reference sections, on maps, or on databases with the full citation: Olson, D.M., E. Dinerstein, E.D. Wikramanayake, N.D. Burgess, G.V.N. Powell, E.C. Underwood, J.A. D'Amico, H.E. Strand, J.C. Morrison, C.J. Loucks, T.F. Allnutt, J.F. Lamoreux, T.H. Ricketts, I. Itoua, W.W. Wettengel, Y. Kura, P. Hedao, and K. Kassem. 2001. Terrestrial ecoregions of the world: A new map of life on Earth. BioScience 51(11):933-938. Sherman, K. and T. Laughlin. 1992. The large marine ecosystem (LME) concept and its application to regional marine resources management. Marine Conservation Development Reports, Gland, Switzerland.

Type of source media: online
Source contribution:
Attribute and geospatial data


Date: 2001 (change 1 of 3) 
We began by accepting the biogeographic realms of Pielou (1979) and Udvardy (1975) and modifying the biome systems of Dinerstein et al. (1995) and Ricketts et al. (1999). We then consulted existing global maps of floristic or zoogeographic provinces, global and regional maps of units based on the distribution of selected groups of plants and animals, the world's biotic province maps, and global maps of broad vegetation types. These were useful for evaluating the extent of realms and biomes, the first two tiers in our hierarchical classification. 

We then identified published regional classification systems to be used as a baseline for ecoregion boundaries. Data and consultations from regional experts were also important for final ecoregion delineations.

Data sources produced in this process: 
World Wildlife Fund 


Date: 20021017 (change 2 of 3) 
The following steps were performed by ESRI: Downloaded the data set from World Wildlife Fund's FTP site. Removed excess attributes. Adjusted order of attributes. Made field names match World Wildlife Fund Terrestrial Ecoregions'. Renamed the data set. Created ArcGIS&#174; layer file (.lyr), projection file (.prj), and spatial indices. Converted the data set to SDC.

Data sources used in this process: 
World Wildlife Fund 


Date: 20050211 (change 3 of 3) 
The following steps were performed by ESRI: Reduced the attribute width of G200_REGION. Created regions reducing the features from 48 to 43.</statement>
      </dataLineage>
      <dqScope>
         <scpLvl>
            <ScopeCd value="005" />
         </scpLvl>
      </dqScope>
   </dqInfo>
   <mdFileID Sync="TRUE">{2217A4D6-4FBB-413F-B9F5-331AE236230E}</mdFileID>
   <distinfo>
      <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
   </distinfo>
</metadata>