<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>ML InfoMap Pvt. Ltd.</origin>
				<pubdate>2006</pubdate>
				<title>Goa Village Map</title>
				<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
				<onlink>http://map.princeton.edu/data/0k/22/5c/70/3/content/restricted/data.zip</onlink>
			</citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>Socio-Demographic and Economic Census data for Goa</abstract>
			<purpose>Map provides socio-demographic and economic census data in GIS file format.</purpose>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>2001</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>ground condition</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>As needed</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc>73.6875</westbc>
				<eastbc>74.4175</eastbc>
				<northbc>15.8028</northbc>
				<southbc>14.8970</southbc>
			</bounding>
		</spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>Location</themekey>
				<themekey>Villages</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekey>India</placekey>
				<placekey>Goa</placekey>
			</place>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>Access granted to Licensee only.</accconst>
		<useconst>LICENSE AGREEMENTThis is a legal agreement between Princeton University Library, the end user, and ML Infomap Pvt. Ltd., map data provider. 1.	The data either contained on the media in the package, or which you have downloaded and all related materials including documentation (collectively, the " ML Infomap Data") are provided by ML Infomap subject to the following terms and conditions:YOU MAY(1)	place the ML Infomap Data on the Princeton University Library network while acknowledging the data source from ML Infomap(2)	install and store ML Infomap Data on a storage device such as a network server, used to access the Data on your other network computers over an internal network(3)	Use ML Infomap Data for academic/research purposes of the users of the Princeton University Library facility(4)	Make derivative works, including but not limited to translations, adaptations, arrangements or maps or other output generated with the ML Infomap Data by acknowledging the data source from ML Infomap(5)	Publish maps and other results of analysis from ML Infomap Data in academic/research journals with proper source referencing to ML Infomap.YOU MAY NOT (1)	Use ML Infomap Data for any commercial purpose whatsoever without specific written agreement with ML Infomap(2)	copy, decode, reverse engineer the ML Infomap Data (3)	rent, lease or lend the ML Infomap Data. (4)	place the ML Infomap Data on the Internet or any similar network or network service except the Princeton University Library network(5)	enter into any reseller, distribution or third party arrangements for such distribution as, but not limited to, electronic, on line, subscription, "fee for service" or general, uncontrolled availability to the public without a prior written agreement with ML Infomap. 2.	SECURITY(1)	Princeton University Library can make one backup copy of the ML Infomap Data, provided that all ML Infomap information including copyright and disclaimer notices are maintained, and possession of the copy is retained by you in a secure location. (2)	In addition, Princeton University Library agrees to use reasonable efforts to protect the ML Infomap Data from unauthorized use, reproduction, distribution or publication. (3)	All rights not specifically granted in this License are reserved by ML Infomap.3.	 LIMITED WARRANTY COVERING THE PHYSICAL MEDIA: ML Infomap warrants to the original Licensee, that the media on which the ML Infomap Data is recorded are free from defects in materials and workmanship under normal use and service FOR A PERIOD OF NINETY (90) DAYS FROM THE DATE OF LICENSE PURCHASE as evidenced by a copy of the receipt. ML Infomap's will replace defective media within this time.4.	 DISCLAIMER REGARDING THE ML INFOMAP DATA: THE ML INFOMAP DATA IS PROVIDED "AS IS." EXCEPT AS MAY OTHERWISE BE EXPRESSLY SET FORTH HEREIN, ML INFOMAP MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WITH RESPECT TO THE ML INFOMAP DATA OR THE RELATED MATERIALS, INCLUDING BY WAY OF EXAMPLE AND NOT LIMITATION, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF TITLE, MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  BY WAY OF FURTHER EXAMPLE AND NOT LIMITATION, ML INFOMAP MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, WITH RESPECT TO THE ACCURACY, RELIABILITY OR COMPLETENESS OF THE ML INFOMAP DATA OR THE RELATED MATERIALS. THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE USE OF THE ML INFOMAP DATA AND THE RELATED MATERIALS IS ASSUMED BY YOU.  IN NO EVENT SHALL ML INFOMAP BE LIABLE TO YOU OR ANY OTHER PERSON, REGARDLESS OF THE CAUSE, FOR THE EFFECTIVENESS OR ACCURACY OF THE ML INFOMAP DATA OR THE RELATED MATERIALS, OR FOR ANY SPECIAL, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES ARISING FROM OR OCCASIONED BY YOUR USE OF THE ML INFOMAP DATA OR THE RELATED MATERIALS, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.  IN THE EVENT THE FOREGOING IS FOUND BY A COURT OF COMPETENT JURISDICTION TO BE INEFFECTIVE, YOU HEREBY AGREE THAT ML INFOMAP MAXIMUM LIABILITY FOR ANY CLAIM ARISING IN CONNECTION WITH THE ML INFOMAP DATA (WHETHER IN CONTRACT, TORT, INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE, PRODUCT</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>Tsering Wangyal Shawa</cntper>
					<cntorg>Princeton University</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>609-258-6804</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>shawatw@princeton.edu</cntemail>
				<hours>8:45 am - 5:00 pm</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<secinfo>
			<secclass>Unclassified</secclass>
		</secinfo>
		<native>Microsoft Windows Vista Version 6.0 (Build 6001) Service Pack 1; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.0.1770</native>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<lineage>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Data was extracted from map scale 1:1 milion, and the map data source was from the Survey of India.</procdesc>
				<procdate>20091106</procdate>
				<proctime>09315400</proctime>
			</procstep>
		</lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<geograph>
				<geogunit>Decimal degrees</geogunit>
			</geograph>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>D_WGS_1984</horizdn>
				<ellips>WGS_1984</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137.000000</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298.257224</denflat>
			</geodetic>
		</horizsys>
	</spref>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
				</cntaddr>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20091109</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>Princeton University</cntorg>
					<cntper>Tsering Wangyal Shawa</cntper>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>REQUIRED: The mailing and/or physical address for the organization or individual.</addrtype>
					<city>REQUIRED: The city of the address.</city>
					<state>REQUIRED: The state or province of the address.</state>
					<postal>REQUIRED: The ZIP or other postal code of the address.</postal>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>609-258-6804</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>shawatw@princeton.edu</cntemail>
				<hours>8:45 am - 5:00 pm</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc>local time</mettc>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink>
			<metprof>ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof>
		</metextns>
	</metainfo>
<Esri><PublishedDocID>{AFB26A16-F50C-48CE-8CBF-16440C502640}</PublishedDocID><PublishStatus>Published</PublishStatus></Esri><mdFileID>{AFB26A16-F50C-48CE-8CBF-16440C502640}</mdFileID></metadata>